contractoruk.com 2018-10-19

# Privacy Statement

**_Contractor UK Ltd_ revised website privacy notice. Published May 2018.**

## **Introduction**

ContractorUK Ltd (contractoruk.com) is a source of information and news for contractors. ContractorUK keeps contractors informed on tax issues, market demand, jobs, IR35, new legislation and more. Our services are business centric and as such our collection and processing of your personal data is in regard to the fulfilment of our business aims.

We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we take that seriously. This Privacy Notice describes ContractorUK Ltd policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data and sets forth your privacy rights. We recognise that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from time to time update this Privacy Notice as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.

## **Data Protection Officer**

ContractorUK Ltd is headquartered in London in the United Kingdom. ContractorUK Ltd have not appointed an internal data protection officer as our processing is not of a type or scale that requires one. However, should you have any questions or concerns about ContractorUK Ltd __ personal data policies or practices, you can contact us at anytime:

Contractor UK Limited  
1 Northumberland Avenue  
Trafalgar Square  
London  
WC2N 5BW

Contractor UK Ltd registered in England No. 03574763

0207 872 5448  

## **How we collect and use (process) your personal information**

### **1\. Personal information you give to us:**

**A. Corporate Customers**  
When you become a customer of ContractorUK Ltd, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your employer’s name, your work address (including your country location), and your email address.

We process your personal information under the General Data Protection Regulation Article (6)(b) to provide you will the product / service you have purchased, undertake standard business functions such as billing, and to inform you of relevant events, content, and other benefits or opportunities. ContractorUK Ltd may also use this information to help us understand our customers’ needs and interests, to better tailor our products and services to meet those needs.

**Registered Users - Newsletters**

When you become a registered user of ContractorUK, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, and email address. We collect these details for the purposes of sending a newsletter.

We process your personal information under the General Data Protection Regulation Article (6)(b) in order to provide you with information and internet forum services. We may also process this information to undertake standard business functions and under the General Data Protection Regulation Article (6)(f) to inform you of relevant events, content, and other benefits or opportunities. ContractorUK Ltd may also use this information to help us understand our customers’ needs and interests, to better tailor our products and services to meet those needs.

**B. Publications**

ContractorUK Ltd offers a great deal of content on our website. In addition to producing original content, ContractorUK Ltd also subscribes to news feeds and blogs produced by others, which we often link to from our website. This means you may find yourself on the ContractorUK Ltd website or reading an email from ContractorUK Ltd and we will offer you a link to another organization’s website where you will find content that we feel will be relevant and useful to you. At these times, you will be leaving the ContractorUK Ltd website. ContractorUK Ltd is not responsible or liable for content provided by these third-party websites or personal information they may happen to gather from you.

You may manage your subscriptions to ContractorUK Ltd newsletters by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time. If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences with ContractorUK Ltd, please contact us at [editor@contractoruk.com](mailto:editor@contractoruk.com).

ContractorUK Ltd uses Google Analytics to track how often people gain access to or read our content. We use this information in the aggregate to understand what content our customers find useful or interesting, so we can produce the most valuable content and services to meet your needs.

**C. Your correspondence** **with the** **ContractorUK Ltd**

If you correspond with us by email, the postal service, or other form of communication, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to your inquiry; to notify you of ContractorUK Ltd services; or to keep a record of your complaint and the like. As always, if you wish to have ContractorUK Ltd “erase” your personal information or otherwise refrain from communicating with you, please contact us at: [editor@contractoruk.com](mailto:editor@contractoruk.com).

**D. Purposes for processing your data**

As explained above, ContractorUK Ltd processes your data to provide you or the company you work for, with the goods or services you have requested or purchased from us. We use this information to refine our goods and services to better tailor them to your needs and to communicate with you about other services we offer that may assist your business.

### 2\. Personal information we get from third parties

ContractorUK Ltd does not receive personal information about individuals from third parties.

### 3\. What happens if you don’t give us your data

You can enjoy much of the information on our website without giving us your personal data. Some personal information is necessary so that ContractorUK Ltd can supply you with the forum service you have requested or newsletters, and to authenticate you so that we know it is you and not someone else. You may cancel your forum account or newsletter subscription at any time and your details will be erased.

## **Use of the** **ContractorUK Ltd** **Website**

As is true of most other websites, ContractorUK Ltd website collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of our website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit our users’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyse trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. ContractorUK Ltd website also uses cookies, web beacons and click tracking. It does not track users when they cross to third party websites, does not provide targeted advertising to them, and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.

  * **Cookies, web beacons and click tracking**

Cookies are pieces of data that a Web site transfers to a user's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage, e-mail response and tracking. Click tracking is a means of measuring the number of clicks a particular advert/image/banner receives.

The Site uses cookies to provide enhanced functionality on the site (e.g., user ID and password prompts) and aggregate traffic data (e.g., what pages are the most popular). These cookies may be delivered in a first-party or third-party context. ContractorUK Ltd may also use cookies, click tracking and web beacons in association with e-mails delivered by ContractorUK Ltd. Our Site also captures limited information (user-agent, HTTP referrer, last URL requested by the user, client-side and server-side clickstream) about visits to our Site; we may use this information to analyse general traffic patterns, to perform routine system maintenance or to provide our clients with metrics related to the success of their recruitment campaign. You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purposes of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using ContractorUK Ltd website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

## **When and how we share information with others**

**Registered Users:**

When you register with ContractorUK we create an account for you and store your data in one of our UK based servers.

**Corporate Clients:**

As a client of ContractorUK we create an account for you and may store your data in our USA based CRM system and UK based finance system.

**In both cases:**

We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) it’s in connection with a request, from you, for information about a service offering from one of our partner organisations; (3) the information is provided to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (4) the information is provided to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (5) to address emergencies or acts of God; or (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating legal authority to act on your behalf. We may also gather aggregated data about our customers and Site visitors and disclose the results of such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to our partners, service providers, advertisers and/or other third parties for marketing or promotional purposes.

The ContractorUK Ltd website uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to "like" or share information from the ContractorUK Ltd website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.

**Company Formations:**

If you choose to use our Company Formation Service we will transfer the data you supply us to Companies House in the UK, to enable the formation and registration of your company. We will then forward the formation documentation to you once we have received it. The information requested is required as per the UK’s Companies Act 2006, more information about this can be found here: <https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2006/46/contents>

We will also keep a record of your company formation for our own records.

## **Transferring personal data from the EU to the US**

ContractorUK Ltd has its headquarters and main servers here in the United Kingdom. We also utilise the CRM services of a company located in the United States (Salesforce) to store information about our corporate clients. Information we collect from you will be processed in either the UK or the USA. The United States have not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union under Article 45 of the GDPR. ContractorUK Ltd relies on the USA Privacy Shield to govern the transfer of data to the USA. In particular, ContractorUK Ltd collects and transfers to the USA personal data only: with your consent; to perform a contract with you; or to fulfil a compelling legitimate interest of ContractorUK Ltd in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. ContractorUK Ltd endeavours to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with ContractorUK Ltd and the practices described in this Privacy Notice. ContractorUK Ltd also minimizes the risk to your rights and freedoms by minimising the data that we collect and store about you.

## **Data subject rights**

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects. A good explanation of them (in English) is available on the website of the United Kingdom’s [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-gdpr/individuals-rights/the-right-to-be-informed/).

This Privacy Notice is intended to provide you with information about what personal data ContractorUK Ltd collects about you and how it is used. If you have any questions, please contact us at [editor@contractoruk.com](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk).

If you wish to confirm that ContractorUK Ltd is processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data we may have about you, please contact us at [editor@contractoruk.com.](mailto:support@technojobs.co.uk)

You may also request information about: the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal data concerned; who else outside of ContractorUK Ltd might have received the data from us; what the source of the information was (if you didn’t provide it directly to us); and how long it will be stored. You have a right to correct (rectify) the record of your personal data maintained by us if it is inaccurate. You may request that we erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain exceptions. You may also request that ContractorUK Ltd cease using your data for direct marketing purposes. In many countries, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how ContractorUK Ltd processes your personal data. When technically feasible, ContractorUK Ltd will—at your request—provide your personal data to you or transmit it directly to another controller.

Reasonable access to your personal data will be provided at no cost upon request made to ContractorUK Ltdat editor@contractoruk.com. If access cannot be provided within a reasonable time frame, we will provide you with a date when the information will be provided. If for some reason access is denied, we will provide an explanation as to why access has been denied.

## **What legal basis do ContractorUK rely on to process personal information?**

  * Consent (this can be withdrawn at any time)
  * To fulfil a contract (either a paid for clients or providing a newsletter with news featured on our website)
  * Legitimate interest (including relevant and tailored communications related to contracting and selling and supplying advertising services to our customers)
  * Legal Obligations (to comply with any legal representations)

## **Security of your information**

To help protect the privacy of data and personally identifiable information you transmit through use of this Site, we maintain a range of physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We restrict access to your personal data to those employees and clients who need to know that information to provide benefits or services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees' privacy responsibilities.

## **Data storage and retention**

Your personal data is stored by ContractorUK Ltd on its servers, and on the servers of the Customer Relationship Management company that we engage, located in the United States. ContractorUK Ltd retains data for the duration of the users or business relationship with us. For more information on where and how long your personal data is stored, and for more information on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact our privacy officer at [editor@contractoruk.com](mailto:editor@contractoruk.com).

## **Changes and updates to the Privacy Notice**

By using this Site, you agree to the terms and conditions contained in this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use and/or any other agreement that we might have with you. If you do not agree to any of these terms and conditions, you should not use this site or any ContractorUK Ltd services. You agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use, or any other agreement we have with you, will be governed by the laws of the United Kingdom.

As our business changes from time to time, this Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use at this Site. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and terms and conditions and will e-mail customers of material changes thereto, but you should check our Site frequently to see the current Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use that is in effect and any changes that may have been made to it. The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or statements regarding our privacy practices and the terms and conditions that govern the use of this Site.

## **Questions, concerns or complaints**

Please contact our privacy officer at the address below:

Contractor UK Limited  
1 Northumberland Avenue  
Trafalgar Square  
London  
WC2N 5BW

0207 872 5448
